Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to make our enemy attack and damage our player character.
To get started, let's head over to our skeleton animation source.
And I want you to create a new animation sequence and just call this Scampton attack.
Then under animation data set the Scampton attack flipbook and just zoom out a bit.
Now we're going to make it attack similar to how all player character attacks frame at the frame where
the Scampton is going to play a character with the sword.
We are going to add an enemy notifier.
So right click and select add notify new notify and call this Scampton.
Actually call this enemy attack.
Then if we just close this, then if we head over to Oscar into an animation blueprint.
We're going to use a jump to Node whenever our Stanton attacks our player character.
So if we just right click and go jump and call this attack event.
And I want to take a minute or drag off here and go to an animation state.
This animation state will be the skeleton attacking soda stores attack.
And if we hadn't said, Here I am going to play the skeleton attacking animation.
So this one plays Kelly attack.
And I hope this up here.
Then if we head back to our new state machine, drag from attack to our idle slash walk.
So in order to go from our attacking back to our normal state, we're going to wait for our attacking
animation to be over.
So just right click and a four time remaining skeleton attack and off the return value.
We'll check to see if this is less than 0.1.
And if this is true, then we'll go back to our normal state.
So we just hook this up here and then go compile.
Next, let's go to our skeleton blueprint.
Open it up.
And I want you to go over to the viewport, and I want you to go ahead and look for a box collision.
So that's it.
Now move this box in front of us.
And then we're basically going to make it that whenever our player character enters this box.
Oscar is going to try and attack them.
It's a bit small.
So using the box extent, let's just increase the size of our box.
So increase it in the Z so it's a bit taller.
And also increase it in the X, so it's a bit thicker.
Just so that we can see this in the game.
But demonstration purposes with the box selected.
I'm going to go to details and look for hidden and just uncheck hidden and game.
That way.
I'm going to see this box when I'm in my game.
Then if we just close this and scroll down, I won't need to go to on component begin overlap.
So this on component can overlap will basically fire when something enters this box.
When something enters this box, we're going to check to see if it's the player character.
So all other actor look for equal.
And we're going to be checking to see if this is equal to our player character.
So just right click and forget player character.
Then it was a struggle paying off a branch and hook us up.
So if I'll play a character that does enter in this box, then we're going to tell the game that our
Stanton is entering attack mode.
So create a new variable and call it attack mode.
And when this happens, we're going to set attack mode to be true.
To just put up here and check out one more thing.
We just scroll out and go over to our handle movement.
When our Scantron is attacking our player character, I don't want it to move.
So under the handle movement, add another condition to the OR and it's simply going to be the attack
note that we just made.
So our attack mode and hook us up here.
Okay, So after we tell the game, the captain is in attack mode.
We are going to tell the game that we should play the skin tone attacking animation.
So the way we're going to do that is by using a timer.
So if we just drag up here and course set timer by event.
And of the Return Valley.
Just right click and promote this terrible and call this attack event.
On the time, just check one and just check this looping box, just drag off this event and therefore
add custom event and call the tone attack.
So the way this custom event will work is every one second is going to file this event.
And what we're going to do is just drag in our animation component, drag up here and look for an instance.
And from here, we'll drag off and look for the jump to Node.
And we're going to jump to, oh, forget what it's called.
So I call it attack event.
So just copy this and paste this here and then connect this into here.
So every one second will pull the jump to node attack event and this will make my scan delay the attack
animation.
So I actually never set up what will happen when my skeleton attacks.
It's going to be very similar to our player VP where we made it attack.
So here where we basically get our out as location, we get a couple of units in front of them and then
we do a line trace for objects.
If we hit something, we then apply damage to it.
I'm just going to do this again in the skeleton.
I'm just going to redo it just to get familiar with the nodes.
So if we just right click and add custom event and we'll call this attack.
When this is called, we're going to do a line trace.
Four objects.
Whether this is going to start.
We're going to right click and we'll get actor location.
Whether it will end or just right click and forget.
Actor Forward Victor.
And we'll just drag up here.
And look for multiply.
And we just right click here and break the split structure pin.
We will put a value in the x.
I'm going to put 100.
So we'll check 100 units in front of us in the forward vector.
And we're just going to add this.
And this will be our ending location.
The type of object we're going to be looking for is going to be a --.
So if we just drag up here for make array and let's just select pawn.
Then if we just drag off our hit or break hit result.
We can check that the actor is equal to a black actor from rock and roll equal.
And here I'm going to look at player character.
If this is true, by the way, there's a shortcut.
You can just click B and left click and branch.
If that is true.
We will apply damage to them.
So just drag up here and look for apply damage.
The massive damage I'm going to do is going to be won and we'll just hook up through to here.
I'm going to compile this.
Then head back to my Scranton animation blueprint and go over to the receive notify enemy attack.
When we call this 95 and I'm going to drag in my skin beep, and I'm going to call the attack customer
that just made.
We can just go compile and go back to our scans and beep.
So if our player character enters this box, the Scantron will continually attack him.
However, if our player character stops and leaves this box, we need to make our skeleton stop attacking
and go back to his normal behavior.
So I'm going to select this box, scroll down and go to one component and over that.
And I'm just going to move this here.
On component and overlap.
We're going to check to see if our player character has left our box.
So look for equal.
And here, I'll just copy this.
So if the other actor is able to play a character and it leaves our box, we're going to have a branch.
And we'll tell the game that we should turn off the attack mode.
So look for attack mode and make sure it's untrue.
And then to stop this custom event, we're going to clear this event.
We can do that by just dragging in this variable.
And looking for clear and invalidate timeout by handler and this will stop the custom event.
And now I have compile and go play.
We can test this all out.
So let me jump in front of my enemy.
If I stand, that should attack me to.
It does this animation.
It does a line trace.
It hits me and I get damaged.
If I leave, then we will stop attacking.
And then we'll do it.
No normal walking stuff.
So with that, our enemy can attack and damage our player character.
Pretty cool.
One more thing.
I just want to comment on my notes before everything gets a bit messy.
So off of here, I'm going to come on and call this handle damage.
I am going to direct this over here.
And I'm going to come on this handle attack system.
Okay.
That's all for this lecture.